In an age of darkness, one man will face the ultimate battle against evil.
Black Death is a drama, history, horror film directed by Christopher Smith.
As the plague decimates medieval Europe, rumours
circulate of a village immune from the plague.
There is talk of a necromancer who leads the
village and is able to raise the dead.
A fearsome knight joined by a cohort of soldiers and a young
monk are charged by the church to investigate.
Their journey is filled with danger, but it's upon entering
the village that their true horror begins.
Ulric, played by Sean Bean.
Osmund, played by Eddie Redmayne.
Langiva, played by Carice van Houten.
Averill, played by Kimberley Nixon.
Wolfstan, played by John Lynch.
Hob, played by Tim McInnerny.
Black Death is a 2010 action horror film directed by Christopher
Smith from an original screenplay by Dario Poloni.
It stars Sean Bean, Eddie Redmayne and Carice van Houten.
Despite not being credited as a writer, Smith made very significant changes
in the second half of the script, including a new ending.
All the scenes of Black Death were shot in
chronological order, a rare occurrence.
The film explores themes of witch, inquisition, monk, village, battlefield.
The tone is dark and emotional.